Hyunsung Cho

■ hyunsungcho@kaist.ac.kr

★ http://hyunsungcho.com

Choch-o

RESEARCH INTERESTS

Ubiquitous computing, context-aware computing, human-computer interaction, social computing

HIGHLIGHTS

• Research experience and publications in ubiquitous computing and mobile HCI

[c.1-3][p.1-3]

Research experience in multi-modal sensing (audio, motion) and machine learning

[c.2][p.1][p.2]

• Experience in machine learning applications

[c.2][t.1-5]

Strong acoustic signal processing skills

[c.2][p.1][p.2][t.2][t.3][t.5]

Basic embedded SW and hardware prototyping skills

[t.1]

EDUCATION

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)

Mar. 2020 -

Ph.D. in Computer Science

Networking & Mobile Systems Lab. Advisor: Sung-Ju Lee

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)

Mar. 2018 - Feb. 2020

M.S. in Computer Science

Networking & Mobile Systems Lab. Advisor: Sung-Ju Lee

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)

Aug. 2013 - Feb. 2018

B.S. in Computer Science (Software Advanced Major)

Magna Cum Laude

PUBLICATIONS

Conference & Journal Papers

[c.2] Knocker: Vibroacoustic-based Object Recognition with Smartphones.

Taesik Gong, **Hyunsung Cho**, Bowon Lee, and Sung-Ju Lee.

UbiComp 2019: ACM Annual Conference on Interactive, Mobile, and Ubiquitous Technologies

[c.1] Intelligent Positive Computing with Mobile, Wearable, and IoT Devices: Literature Review and Research Directions.

Uichin Lee, Kyungsik Han, **Hyunsung Cho**, Kyong-Mee Chung, Hwajung Hong, Sung-Ju Lee, Youngtae Noh, Sooyoung Park, and John M. Caroll.

Ad Hoc Neworks Journal, Voulme 83, 2019

Posters, Demos, and Workshop Papers

[p.3] Sender-Controlled Mobile Instant Message Notifications Using Activity Information.

Hyunsung Cho, Jinyoung Oh, Juho Kim, and Sung-Ju Lee.

MobiSys 2019 Demos: ACM International Conference on Mobile Systems, Applications and Services

[p.2] Real-Time Object Identification with a Smartphone Knock.

Taesik Gong, **Hyunsung Cho**, Bowon Lee, and Sung-Ju Lee.

MobiSys 2019 Videos: ACM International Conference on Mobile Systems, Applications and Services

Best Video Award

[p.1] Identifying Everyday Objects with a Smartphone Knock.

Taesik Gong, Hyunsung Cho, Bowon Lee, and Sung-Ju Lee.

CHI 2018 Extended Abstract: ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems

WORK EXPERIENCE

KAIST Networking and Mobile Systems Lab (NMSL), Daejeon, South Korea

Research Assistant

Advisor: Sung-Ju Lee. Research on novel applications of mobile sensing for context-aware services.

Kiswe Mobile Inc., New Providence, NJ, USA

Jun. 2017 - Aug. 2017

Web Frontend Developer

Developed a trivia widget for interactive mobile sports streaming service. The widget was included in the live service for the IAAF Diamond League event in collaboration with VRT Sporza. The service was covered in press. Developed tools to support video streamers such as a multi-view layout editor for multi-cam videos; an easy drag-and-drop thumbnail uploader; and a live streaming control interface.

KAIST Interaction Lab (KIXLAB), Daejeon, South Korea

Dec. 2015 - Feb. 2017

Research Intern

Advisers: Jihee Kim and Juho Kim. Research on analysis of presidential election promises in relation with government budget expenditure data through crowdsourcing.

COURSE PROJECTS

GCT634 Musical Applications of Machine Learning

[t.5] Bass Instrument Source Separation

Developed a convolutional autoencoder-based bass instrument source separation model to extract bass sound from a multi-instrument music source [report] [github]

[t.4] Music Generation

Developed an RNN model that generates musical note sequences [github]

[t.3] Music Genre Classification

Developed a CNN model to classify audio files into different music genres [report] [github]

[t.2] Musical Instrument Classification

Developed a machine learning model to classify audio files into different music instruments using multiple audio features [report] [github]

KSE624 Mobile and Pervasive Computing

[t.1] Smart Shoes for Bouncing Leg Detection

Designed and built e-textile based smart shoes that detect whether the shoe wearer is bouncing a leg or not [ppt] [github]

AWARDS & HONORS

Best TA Award	2019

KAIST School of Computing

Google Women Techmakers Scholars

2019

\$1K Academic scholarship, awarded based on academic performance, leadership, and impact on the community of women in tech

Best Video Award	2019
3 5 1 10 - 2010 F - 27	

MobiSys 2019 [p.2]

Best Poster/Demo Award 2018

ACM SIGCHI Local Chapter [p.1]

Undergraduate Research Program 2016

\$2K Research grant awarded by KAIST

2nd Place, The 3rd Korea SW Hackathon 2016

\$3K Award by the Ministry of Science, ICT and Future Planning of Republic of Korea

National Science & Technology Scholarship 2014 - 2017

Merit-based scholarships

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Mar. 2017 - Present

Head Teaching Assistant, KAIST

CS341 Introduction to Computer Networks

Invited Student Panel, KAIST

CS492 Introduction to Research (invited by Juho Kim, Sung-Ju Lee, and Shin Yoo)

Teaching Assistant, KAIST

CS341 Introduction to Computer Networks

Teaching Assistant, KAIST

CS101 Introduction to Programming

Fall 2016 - Fall 2017

Spring 2019

Spring 2019

Fall 2018

INVITED TALKS

Vibroacoustic-based Object Recognition with Smartphones

2019 IAT (Information Accessibility Technology) Conference

Nov. 22, 2019

EXTRACURRICULAR EXPERIENCE

MADCAMP (Mobile Application Development Camp)

Dec. 2016 - Feb. 2017

Intensive, focused development camp where I developed five different mobile applications in 4.5 weeks. Example apps are a humming-based multi-play music quiz game and a group alarm clock that ensures every member to wake up.

SPARCS (Developers Club), KAIST

Mar. 2014 - Dec. 2016

Head of Server Management Group & Web Developer

Managed over 10 physical and virtual server machines as the leader of the club's server management group. Developed a server monitoring tool using gRPC. Held seminars on the basics of server management for students. Topics include Linux, LDAP, mail server, file system, and security.

SELECTED PRESS

Electronics Weekly, Sensor fusion lets phone identify objects by simply knocking against them	Oct. 2019
Science Daily, Object identification and interaction with a smartphone knock	
NEW ATLAS, Smartphone tech recognizes objects by being knocked against them	
Nerdiest, This algorithm makes smartphones recognize objects just by Knocking them	
ICT NEWS, New application allows you to identify an object by tapping it with a smartphone	
Sporza, Sporza biedt interactieve primeur met Kiswe Mobile tijdens Diamond League Brussel	

TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Programming Languages Python, Java, Kotlin, Javascript, C++, C, MATLAB

Mobile DevelopmentAndroid, React NativeHardware PrototypingArduino, e-textilesBackend DevelopmentDjango, Node, Express

Web Frontend Development React, Vue.js, AngularJS, jQuery, D3.js, HTML, CSS

Database Firebase, MySQL, MongoDB

Tools Git/Github, Vim, LaTex, Markdown, Slack